（科罗拉多州 曲水联邦监狱）
（耶和华说 你弃绝了我）
- 嗨 你醒了 - 是啊
- Yo, are you up? - Yeah.
杰克斯明天会先动手
Jax has got the jump on you tomorrow.
两点钟
Two bell.
算是还你人情
I figure I owe you.
嗨 听见了吗
Yo. Did you hear what I said?
听见了
I heard.
谢谢
Thanks.
所有人都趴下 快 趴在地上
Everybody down now! On the ground!
你 犯人 趴在地上
You! Inmate! On the ground!
趴下
Down!
- 趴下 - 听见了吗
- Get down! - You heard him!
给我趴下
On the fucking ground!
《金蝉脱壳》
（禁闭室 曲水联邦监狱 隔离区）
该你了
You're up.
左转
To your left.
站在线上
On the line.
行了
All right…
站在右边
Step to the right.
进去吧
Let's go.
手
Hands.
好好享受
Enjoy.
靠着墙
Against the wall.
走吧
Let's go.
吃午饭了 犯人 吃点素的吧
Lunchtime, inmate. Eat your veggies.
（巧克力牛奶）
行了
There you go.
嗨 罗格
Hey, Roag!
干嘛
Yeah?
现在几点
Got the time?
管这干嘛 要去约会
Fuck you care? You got a date?
不是
No.
要不把你妹妹介绍给我
Maybe you got a sister or a cousin?
你想找揍吗
Wanna get your head smashed?
不 不想
No, not really.
差5分4点
It's five to 4:00.
自作聪明
Wise ass.
嗨 基佬 走吧
Hey, Fruitcake! Let's go.
2 3 4
Two… Three… Four…
5 6 7
Five… Six… Seven…
Eight…
Nine…
Ten…
290 291
290… 291…
292 293
292… 293…
294…
295 296
295… 296…
297 298
297… 298…
299 300
299… 300.
怎么回事
What the fuck…
快走
Come on!
到底出了什么事
What the fuck's going on?
2号门发生火灾 让所有犯人都回到牢房里
We've got a fire, gate two. All prisoners back to their cells.
明白
Copy that.
（圣经）
该死的
What the fuck…
有人跑了 重复 有犯人跑了
We got a runner! Repeat, prisoner is running!
快走 快走
Let's go, let's go!
（幸运的雷）
绕行不错
Nice look.
是哈什的主意
Hush's idea.
不错吧
Nice, right?
里面怎么样啊 头儿
How was inside, boss man?
棒极了 大家都问你好呢
Inside's great. Everyone's asking about you.
你要是再不出来
If you weren't out soon,
我就会冲进去把你给拎出来
I'd be breaking into that motherfucker and pulling your ass out.
你是头一个出来了还想再进去的人
Only ex-con I know gets out, wants to go back in.
我没说我想 我说我会
I didn't say "wants." I said I would.
这可有区别
There is a difference.
你可省着点用
Don't spend it all in one place.
我们找到一名从曲水监狱越狱出来的犯人
We have an escape from Bendwater Penitentiary.
举起手来 从电话亭里走出来
Step out of the booth with your hands in the air!
好戏开始了
Showtime.
把手举起来
Put your hands in the air! Now!
- 把手举起来 - 把手放在脑后
- Get them up, now! - Hands in the air!
十指交叉 不许动 听到吗 举起手来 不许动
Put your hands on your head! Interlock your fingers! Do not move!
天气真好
Beautiful day.
我是莱斯特·克拉克
Calm down, Warden. I'm Lester Clark.
我是BC安保公司的首席执行官
I'm the CEO of B&C Security.
听说过我们吧 没有？
You might have heard of us. No?
好吧 我们是一家独立的安保公司
All right, well… We're an independent security company.
联邦监狱局雇佣我们
hired by the Federal Bureau of Prisons.
测试他们在全国范围内 高度戒备的监狱的可靠性
to test the integrity of their maximum security facilities nationwide.
这位是雷·布雷斯林 他是我的合伙人
This is Ray Breslin. He's my partner.
同时 也是逃脱大师
and resident Houdini.
监狱长
Warden.
过去七年里 雷被安插在联邦监狱局管辖的
For the last seven years, Ray has been inserted into.
全国每一个高度戒备的监狱里
every maximum incarceration facility in the system.
他的工作是确保这些监狱里的犯人
He is there to ensure that each and every one of them.
百分之百无法逃脱
is 100% escape-proof.
显然你们的监狱不够牢靠 他逃出来了
And apparently yours wasn't, and he got out.
行了 好吧
Okay, fine.
你要说说是怎么做到的吧
I suppose you're gonna tell me how you did it?
还以为他很想知道 我自作多情了
Think he wants to know? Doesn't seem like it.
雷 你就说吧
Ray, you're on.
监狱长 我们从头说起
Warden, let's start from the top.
要越狱得具备三个条件 知道监狱布局
Any break requires three things, knowing the layout,
摸清日常规律 还得有里应或者外合
understanding the routine, and help from outside or in.
了解监狱布局 薄弱点就会明显
If you know the layout, the weak side is obvious.
曲水监狱的薄弱点是禁闭室
In Bendwater's case, it's the Secure Housing Unit.
政府花费了1700万造这座监狱
The government expenditure was 17 million dollars building that facility.
用了最先进的技术
It's state-of-the-art.
唯一的问题是 它紧挨着一个毫无防范的消防车库
The only problem is, it's located next to an unsecured fire garage.
首先我要进入禁闭室 所以我树了些敌人
First I needed to get inside, so I made some enemies.
进去后我发现那儿明显人手不足
Once inside, it was obvious you were short-staffed.
联邦政策建议在押送高风险犯人的时候
Federal guidelines recommend two guards are present.
要有两名狱警 你们只用了一个
when transferring high risk inmates. You only use one.
下一步是摸清狱警的活动规律
Knowing the guards' routine was the next step.
每次放风30秒 看管的狱警会去抽烟
Thirty seconds into my rec time, my CO took a smoke break.
每天有7分钟 没有人监视我
For seven minutes every day, there were no eyes on me.
Two…
Three…
一旦摸清了规律 我要做的就是挑个日子
After I knew the routine, all I had to do was pick the day.
可那个时候你还被关在禁闭室里
But at this point, you were still locked inside a steel box.
要出来 你得有门的密码
To get out, you had to have a key code.
你们的巧克力牛奶很不错
You have very good chocolate milk.
牛奶盒内侧有一层薄薄的蜡片
See, the cartons contain a thin layer of wax laminate.
把它盖在键盘上
Lay it over the keypad,
留下的指印会显示哪四个键被按过
the impression will indicate which four keys were pressed.
有了这四个数字 剩下的就是排列组合的事了
With the four keys, it's just a numbers game to identify the correct sequence.
我只要摸到键盘就行了
I just needed to get to the keypad.
删掉监控录像 我有1分钟
Afterl covered my tracks, I had one minute to make it.
在消防队之前赶到消防车库
to the fire response shed before the team did.
我知道狱警那会儿还在屋顶上浪费时间呢
I knew the guards were still on the roof doing what they do, which is wasting time.
你他妈说什么
What the fuck are you saying?
在你们发现之前我已经出来了
And before you know it, I'm right where I want to be.
正好赶上搭顺风车
Just in time to catch my ride.
你们的消防队把我送出大门
Then your men drove me right off the grounds.
还有问题吗？
You have any questions?
什么样的人会愿意没事整天待在监狱里
What kind of man would choose to spend most of his life in prison?
我们不是针对你个人 监狱长
Don't take it personally, Warden.
这些年 雷从14座监狱里逃脱出来
Over the years, Ray has broken out of 14 of these institutions.
有些人擅长画画 有些人呢 擅长唱歌
Some people have a talent to paint, some to sing.
我很会唱歌
Me, I sing.
雷·布雷斯林拥有一项独特的技能
Ray Breslin, he possesses a unique set of skills.
凡是人设计出来的监狱 他都能逃出来
He is able to break out of any prison designed by man.
你最近规矩吗
So have you been good?
当然 你呢 在里面听话吗
Yeah. You? You a good boy inside?
哦 当然
Of course.
好吧 跟那个男的处得怎么样
Okay… How did that thing with that guy go?
- 哪个男的 - 哪个男的
- What guy? - What guy?
我进去的时候 你准备跟一个笨蛋共进晚餐
When I was going in, you were about to have dinner with some guy, some bozo.
哦 那个 甜点还没上我们就崩了
Oh, yeah. That bozo ended before dessert.
是他没眼光
Well, that's his loss.
是啊 一群窝囊废
Yeah. They're all losers.
我不是早就说了
How many times have I told you that?
回去想吃点什么吗
You want to get something to eat when we get back?
你想说什么
Is there a problem?
你的厨艺很糟
You're a horrible cook.
真会说话 还是明天早上再抱怨吧
That's nice. Well, you can complain in the morning.
噢 见鬼
Ouch.
（加利福尼亚州 洛杉矶）
（BC安保公司）
早上好 先生 有事吗
Morning, sir. How can I help you?
哦 布雷斯林先生 对不起 我是朱丽丝
Mr. Breslin, I'm so sorry. I'm Jules.
没关系 你是新来的
That's okay. You're new here?
不 我已经在这儿五个月了
No, sir. I've been here five months.
- 五个月 - 是的 先生
- Five months? - Yes, sir.
你要给我看什么
What do you got for me?
瞧瞧这个
Check it out.
不错 很聪明
That's good. Very smart.
这都是你自己做的？太棒了 天才
Did you do this all by yourself? I'm impressed. Genius.
你很聪明 不过…
You're smart, but…
抱歉 聪明还不够
Sorry, not smart enough.
别郁闷
Don't be bitter.
布雷斯林先生 大家在会议室等你
Mr. Breslin, they're ready for you in the conference room.
早上好 赖斯 艾碧
Morning, Les. Abby.
杰西卡·梅耶 很荣幸见到你
Jessica Mayer. It's an honor to meet you.
你代表了这个领域的最高水平
Your work is the gold standard in the field.
你取得的成就太了不起了
What you've accomplished is remarkable.
谢谢 你来这儿为了
Thank you. And you're here because…
雷 她是搞情报工作的 是
She's Agency, Ray. As in…
中央情报局的
Central Intelligence Agency.
你是间谍
You a SPY?
更糟 我是个律师
Worse. I'm a lawyer.
雷 好好听她说 她是真的 我跟他们总部确认过
Ray, hear her out. She's legit. I called Langley myself.
好吧 我洗耳恭听 说吧
Fine. I'll just listen. Go ahead.
布雷斯林先生 非常规引渡被禁止使用以后
Mr. Breslin, after ending "extraordinary rendition, " the Agency is looking for.
中央情报局一直在寻找另一种方式
alternate situations for incarcerating the sort of people.
来监禁那些犯下严重罪行的人 哦 怎么说好呢
who commit acts so despicable they're best… Well, how can I put it?
消灭掉
Eliminated?
让他们消失 我们在试验一个样板
Disappeared. And we're currently testing a prototype.
专门接收没有政府愿意要的犯人
to deal with people no government wants on their books.
这些设施是牢不可逃的
these facilities are escape-proof.
才能在全球范围内推广
before the whole system goes online globally.
她的意思是 这玩意儿目前还没有任何官方认可
What she's really saying is that none of this is officially sanctioned by anyone.
差不多
Close.
罗斯小姐 我想说的是
What I'm saying, Miss Ross,
这种监狱都是私人出资和管理的
is that these facilities are privately funded and administered.
所以官方这个词其实不适用
So the word "official" does not really apply.
就是说万一出了什么事
So if anything goes wrong,
你们局里也不会扯上关系
nothing comes back to bite you people in the ass.
喔 这不是你关心的事
This is not your concern.
嗨 我欠他的 不欠你的
Hey! I owe him. I don't owe you.
我的工作是排除我们国家的一切安全隐患
Myjob is to make sure the United States is safe and clean.
行了 别玩虚的了 实话实说吧
All right, can we just cut the crap and call it like it is?
这些机构不受体制约束 没审判 没定罪
These institutions are off the grid. There are no trials, there's no convictions.
那些人就这么消失了
These people are just disappeared.
而你想让他去测试一下
And you want him to go in and test it?
说到这会儿 请允许我插个嘴 他们愿意支付
Maybe it's time for me to interject into the conversation that they have offered.
双倍的费用 也就是500万 提前支付
double your standard fee, that's five mil, right? In advance.
你感兴趣
So you like this?
听着 你是艺术家 我是个商人
Look, I'm a numbers guy. You're the artist, Ray.
从经济效益的角度来说 是的 我非常感兴趣
From a financial standpoint, I like it. Yes, I like it very much.
除了钱 布雷斯林先生
Beyond the money, Mr. Breslin,
被关进这个地方的人
the people that are sent to this place.
不应该再出来
should not be allowed out into the real world.
他们中任何一个都有翻天覆地的本事
Every one of them is a potential game changer. For the worse.
好吧
All right.
行动指南？
Guidelines?
和平时一样 假名字 假身世 联系人 撤离密码 对吗
The usual. Full work. Alias. Cover story. Contact. Evac number. Right?
唯一的区别是 为了能彻底测试那里的安全体系
Well, the only difference is to fully test the security of the system.
不能告诉你们中的任何人那里的位置
it's essential that none of you know the location of the incarceration.
这个会有问题吗
Will that present a problem?
会 当然会有问题
Yes. Yes, it would.
什么时候开始
When do we start?
这就开始了
Wejust did.
你换上新身份 从现在起再过24小时
You and your new identity will be picked up from this location.
会有私人保镖在这个地方把你接走
by private contractors 24 hours from now.
（路易斯安那州 新奥尔良）
我讨厌这任务
I don't like this.
你讨厌那姑娘
And you don't like her.
别自作多情
Don't flatter yourself.
我们这次违背了以往你每次进去时
We're going against every protocol and guideline.
都严格遵循的规程和行动指南
that you yourself have insisted on every single time that you've gone in.
而且我讨厌她
And I don't like her.
你说得对 这活一点也不招人喜欢
You're right. There's nothing to like about any of it.
- 那干嘛还干？- 因为他野心大 又贪心
- Then why do it? - Because he's ambitious and greedy.
被你说得跟缺点似的
You say that like it's a bad thing.
我的身份
Profile.
Ok
好吧
姓名安东尼·普尔图斯 生在马德里 13岁时母亲去世
Name, Anthony Portos. Born Madrid. Mother died when you were 13.
你父亲在美国把你带大
Raised by your father in the U.S.
你是一名制造炸弹的嫌疑犯
You were suspected of manufacturing bombs that have been used.
欧洲和南美有12起政治爆炸案用的是你造的炸弹
in a dozen political bombings across Europe and South America.
在过去十年里
for the last 10 years.
里面的联系人
Contact on site?
监狱长叫罗杰·马什
Warden's name is Roger Marsh.
撤离密码？
Evacuation code?
3-1-0-2-7-5.
好了 开始行动
All right. Let's do it.
植入追踪器
Tag him.
不 我用不着这个
No. I don't need this. Really.
这你用得着 没得商量
Yeah, you do. It's non-negotiable.
你以为我会随便放你走
You think I'm letting you go in cold?
这太老套了
This gets old.
给我爷儿们点
Man the fuck up.
哪天你试试
Try it some time.
嗨 这主意不错 你什么时候想退休
Sounds good, boss man. Any time you want to retire…
我一直学着呢 随时能接班
I've been takin' notes. I'm ready to step up.
我上哪儿去找你这样的技术天才
Where am I gonna find another techno-thug as gifted as you?
天生的怪才
Freak of nature.
是啊 稀有品种
Yeah, very rare.
你在这儿 宝贝儿 追踪器正常
There you are, baby. Transponder's good.
就像我在你的手臂上
It's like having me right on your shoulder.
还想在哪儿
Where else?
嗨 别忘了给我们写信
Hey, don't forget to write us. All right?
抓住
Hold it!
让他睡觉
Put him to sleep.
7458号犯人安东尼·普尔图斯
Prisoner 7458. Anthony Portos.
欢迎你 参加国际监禁中心报到会
Welcome to the International Detainee Unit intake.
我是霍布斯监狱长
I'm Warden Hobbes.
霍布斯 马什监狱长在哪儿
Hobbes. Where's Warden Marsh?
这里没有马什监狱长
There is no Warden Marsh.
是我脑子糊涂 记错了
What, am I disoriented? ls that it?
应该就是这样吧
I guess that must be it.
我也没在运输机上看到有人被杀
And I didn't see a man killed on a transport helicopter.
还被扔出去 对吗
and thrown out either, right?
普尔图斯先生 你已经报到完毕了
Mr. Portos, your intake is finished.
等等
Wait!
我的撤离密码是310275
My evacuation code is 3-1-0-2-7-5.
撤离密码？
Evacuation code?
是的 撤离密码
Yes. Evacuation code.
告诉我几个数字就让你恢复自由
Meaning you give me a number and you walk out of here free as a bird?
不 我不这么想
No. I don't think so.
既然来了 你就是我的
You're here now. And you belong to me.
你已经报到完毕了
Your intake is finished.
等等 等等 我有撤离密码
Wait… I have an evacuation code!
有消息吗
Anything?
跟昨天一样 什么也没有
Getting a ghost bounce, same as yesterday. I can't find him.
查了两次
Twice.
再查一次
Run it again.
A区所有犯人去巴比伦
All prisoners A-Block proceed to Babylon.
All prisoners A-Block to proceed to Babylon.
普尔图斯
Portos.
巴比伦随时都会死人
Everybody's days are numbered in Babylon!
巴比伦 死亡
Babylon, death, death!
嗨
Hey!
不想死就快付钱 去交点朋友 你需要帮手
Go make some friends. You're gonna need them.
我是萨拉姆
嗨
Hey!
趴着别动 趴着别动
Stay down! Stay down!
新来的 你死定了
New fish. We own you!
退后
Back off!
最后警告
Last time.
给我退后
Back away.
普尔图斯
Portos.
洛特梅耶 埃米尔·洛特梅耶
Rottmayer. Emil Rottmayer.
我现在没有心情跟你握手
Really not much in a hand-shaking mood right now.
好吧
Okay.
你的名字
Your name.
第四个火枪手 真是个好名字
The fourth Musketeer. It's a good name.
你怎么会进来的
Why are you in here?
你关心这干嘛
Why do you care?
我以前保护过一个人叫曼海姆的人
I used to work security for a guy by the name of Manheim.
维克多·曼海姆 听说过这个人吗
Victor Manheim. Have you heard of the name?
曼海姆 我想想 没有
Manheim, let me see… No.
- 他是个天才 - 是吗？
- He's a genius. - Really?
他这个人有个习惯 喜欢劫富济贫
He has this habit of taking money from the rich and giving it to the poor.
- 你听说过那故事吗 - 对 我听说过
- You've heard that story before… - I've heard that story. Yeah.
他们想找到他 可我不会帮他们
Now they're trying to find him. But I'm not gonna help them.
- 好吧 - 去他们的
- Okay. - So fuck 'em!
是啊 去他们的
Right. Fuck 'em.
普尔图斯 别被弄死了
Portos, don't get killed.
希望如此
If you say so.
上回他们弄死个人
Last time they killed a guy in here,
把尸体扔在这儿烂了三天
they let his body rot for three days.
哦 害得监狱舞会都取消了
And they canceled the prison dance.
我可不想毁了舞会
Wouldn't want to fuck up the prom.
早上好 长官
Morning, sir.
又是件美丽的作品
That's another beautiful piece, sir.
你骗了我
You lied to me.
- 我骗了你？我不知道 - 不 不
- I lied to you? I'm not sure what… - No, no.
别再说了
You say nothing.
你杀掉的那个人我怎么跟客户交代
What am I supposed to tell the client about the man you killed?
说是他自己跳下去的
That he justjumped, like you said?
我们不能这么随便 人家出钱让我们防止他跳下去
This isn't a free-for-all. We're paid to prevent him from jumping.
我在死人身上可找不到生存证据
And I can't get proof of life from a dead man.
所以
So…
这家伙值的钱就从你工资里扣
You will be docked the entire price of the asset.
这家伙值的钱 相当于我一个月的工资呢
The entire price of the asset equals a month of my pay.
算你运气好 死掉的这个人不是很值钱
Then you're lucky the man you killed was not high value.
走吧 德雷克
That is all, Drake.
普尔图斯 看看他们
Hey, Portosl Look at this.
没有日出 没有日落 可他们 还是一直在祈祷
There's no sunrise, no sunset, but still they pray all the time.
你不觉得这很有意思吗
Don't you find that interesting?
不觉得
Not really.
你像是那种容易对事情感兴趣的人
You look like the kind of a guy that finds things interesting.
以前坐过牢吗
You've done time before?
你干嘛问这么多
Why all the questions?
这样我能了解你
That's how I learn things.
你还是去研究其他人吧
You really ought to study somebody else.
普尔图斯
Portos!
要帮忙吗？
Need a favor?
你真热心
The favor man.
（破解监狱安防系统 雷·布雷斯林著）
嘴上说不感兴趣 可你却一直在观察
For a man who is not interested, you're doing a lot of looking.
你需要什么
What do you need?
我要到隔离区里去
I need to get into the isolation area.
不 你不会想去的
No, you really don't.
不 我一定要去 就当是帮个忙
Yeah, I really do. Call it a favor.
好吗？
Okay?
好吧
Okay.
很好
Good.
这叫帮忙
That's a favor?
有时候打你是帮你
Sometimes favors hurt.
真的？
Really?
- 来吧 - 好吧
- Come on. - Okay.
看你多大能耐
Let's see what you can do.
行啊
All right.
你这家伙是吃素的吧
You hit like a vegetarian.
来啊
Come on.
- 好吧 - 让我瞧瞧
- All right. - Let's see it.
你瞧这个
Try this.
疼吗？
Hurt?
打得不错
That was good.
还有更厉害的
Look what's coming!
放松点 这是假打
Relax. It's pretend.
真是本性难移
Guess boys will be boys.
够了
That's enough.
把他们关进禁闭箱
Put them in the box! Now!
不用急着谢我
You can thank me later.
他们知道他有追踪器
They knew he was tagged.
他们当然知道 你当这些是什么人
Of course they knew. Who do you think these guys are?
你以为他们是联邦监狱局的那些傻帽吗
What do you think, they're a bunch of yahoos from one of those BOP facilities?
这是帮搞情报的 追踪器都是他们发明的
This is the shadow world. These guys, they invented this shit.
他们干嘛付这么多钱
Why do you think they pay us all that money?
想想行动指南
Remember what the guidelines were.
你他妈在说什么？哪有什么行动指南
What the fuck are you talking about? There are no guidelines.
- 马上打给中情局的婊子 - 哈什
- Now, you call that CIA bitch. - Hush…
该死的
Motherfucker.
行啊 我会打的
All right. I'll make the call.
艾碧盖尔 麻烦你让他离我远点 行吗
Abigail, you got to keep him away from me, all right?
胳膊给我
Give me your arm.
一个医生在这种地方怎么工作？
How does a doctor work in a place like this?
你是希望这儿没有医生吗
Would you prefer there wasn't a doctor here?
这是哪儿
Where is "here"?
嗨 医生 动作快点
Hey, Doc, let's wrap it up.
医生
Doc…
你问你什么
What did he ask you?
他…
He…
他想知道自己 脱水的情况跟别人比起来算不算严重
Wanted to know how his dehydration compared to the other detainees.
你怎么跟他说的
And what did you tell him?
关我屁事
I don't care.
我就是这么说的
That's what I told him.
把他带出去
Get him out of there.
你在里面找到要找的东西了吗
Did you find what you were looking for in the box?
所有犯人回到牢房 所有犯人回到牢房
All prisoners back to their cells. All prisoners back to their cells.
你来之前是什么人 普尔图斯
Who were you before you came in here, Portos?
你一直在观察环境 观察所有东西
You're always watching the room, always watching everything.
- 你问我以前是干嘛的 - 对
- Are you asking what I used to do? - Yeah.
可以告诉你 不过你得再帮我个忙
I'll tell you, but I need a little favor.
去你的
Fuck that.
不愿意就算了
All right, don't do it.
行了 我听着呢 这次要我帮什么忙
All right, I'm listening. What's the favor this time?
我要一块金属 大约3英寸宽
I need a piece of metal, about three inches wide.
圆的 光滑的
Round, smooth.
没问题 我去趟五金店 一会儿就回来 好吗
No problem. I'll hit the Home Depot, and I'll be right back. Okay?
如果你弄到这样的金属 我也许能把你弄出去
If you get me that piece of metal, I might be able to get you out of here.
告诉霍布斯我想谈谈
Tell Hobbes I want to talk.
犯人准备接受审讯 犯人准备接受审讯
Interrogation, ready for inmate. Interrogation, ready for inmate.
你在这儿已经六个月了 洛特梅耶先生
You've been here six months now, Mr. Rottmayer.
你知道我们的规矩
So you know how this works.
给你10秒钟
Ten seconds.
维克多·曼海姆在哪儿
Where is Victor Manheim?
对很多人来说 他是个英雄
You know, to many people, he is a hero.
9秒钟
Nine seconds.
你这儿有纸和笔吗
Do you have a pencil and a piece of paper?
8秒钟
Eight seconds.
我给你画张地图
I could draw you a map.
什么地图？
Of what?
找到他的地图
Where you could find him.
我小的时候一直想当个艺术家
When I was a kid, I always wanted to be an artist.
天呐 你的脸皮还真厚
My God, you are pushing it.
问题是我没那个天分
Problem was, I had no talent.
还有6秒
Six seconds.
我试了又试 试了又试 试了又试
I tried and I tried and I tried…
5秒
Five…
你有梦想吗
Do you ever have dreams?
4秒
Four…
还是你一直就想
Or did you always want to be…
- 当这个？- 2秒
- this? - Two…
- 1秒 - 画好了
- One… - Done.
瞧 在这儿
Look. There.
我说了
I told you.
我没天分
No talent.
资料显示你这个人智商很高
The records indicate that you are a highly intelligent man.
如果真是这样我希望你能认清现实
As such, I would have expected you to see the situation.
看清现在的局势
and understand it for what it is.
在这里你什么也控制不了 任人摆布
In here, you have no control over any part of your life,
除了呼吸
except your breathing.
现在连这点特权也没了
And you just lost that privilege.
把他放倒
Get him down!
继续
Keep going.
好了
Enough.
出了什么事？
What happened?
没什么 我还活着
Nothing. I'm still here.
你该告诉我了
Now it's your turn.
我这个人以越狱为生
I break out of prisons for a living.
过去八年里
For the past eight years,
我用越狱的方法 为联邦监狱局测试监狱
I've been breaking out of facilities for the Federal Bureau of Prisons.
霍布斯可能利用了我的报告 把这里设计得牢不可破
I think Hobbes used my reports to make this place unbreakable.
有人要测试这里 其实这是个圈套
Someone wanted this place tested, but it was a set-up.
他们想让我消失 不知道是谁 我会查出来
They wanted to bury me. I don't know who, but I'm gonna find out.
我要你再搞个烟雾弹
I need you to set up another diversion.
这次干嘛
What now?
你得再回禁闭箱
You've got to go back in the box.
门儿都没有
No fucking way.
想出去吗
Want to get outta here?
好吧 我干
Okay. I'll do it.
可如果我出不去 我宰了你
But if I don't get out, I kill you.
很公平
Fair enough.
一次成功的越狱需要具备三个条件
A successful breakout depends on three things,
布局 规律 和帮手
layout, routine, and help.
- 可这些我们一样也没有 - 暂时没有
- But they've taken those away. - For now.
禁闭箱底下有东西 可能是水管
There's something under the box. I think it's a conduit.
如果是 你怎么知道它通向哪儿
If it is, how do you know where it goes?
我不知道 不过我会搞清楚
I don't. But I'm gonna find out.
太恶心了
It's disgusting.
被囚禁的人跟外面的人思考方式不一样
The mind of a man confined works differently than someone on the outside.
看东西角度不同 整个建筑是垂直的
He sees things different. The architecture is vertical.
牢房区 巴比伦 禁闭箱 餐厅
The cell blocks, Babylon, the box, the mess…
所有地方都是巨大的垂直隔间
E verything's in large vertical compartments.
最大的可能 是这地方建在一个地下的天然地峡或者洞穴里
Best guess is they built out underground in large natural fissures and caves.
在垂直结构里 禁闭箱下面的东西七成可能是向上的
In a vertical structure, 70/30 says whatever's under that box goes up.
如果我能进去 顺着它走
If I can get in there, follow where it goes,
也许就能到地面上去
I just might find my way to the surface.
假设你是对的 怎么切开金属地板
Let's say you're right. How do we cut metal?
不用切开 完全用不着
We don't cut. We don't cut at all.
这个地方在地下 空气很潮湿
This place is subterranean. There's moisture in the air.
造这地方的人应该用铝铆钉
Whoever built this place should have used aluminum rivets.
来固定面板 可他们用了钢钉
to hold those panels down, but they used steel.
钢钉时间久了会生锈
Steel rusts over time.
我们就利用这一点 把热量都集中到那些钢钉上
We apply that. We'll concentrate the heat to those rivets.
让它们膨胀 然后自己脱落
and they'll expand and snap right the fuck off.
集中热量
Concentrated heat?
对 用你给我的那块金属
Yeah, from the piece of metal you gave me.
把用牙膏磨炼的金属对着阳光
You expose a toothpaste-polished piece of metal to sunlight…
在100摄氏度的高温下 钢会膨胀0.03立方厘米
At a hundred degrees centigrade, steel expands.03 cubic centimeters.
那些钢钉就会自己脱落
and those rivets are gonna come right off.
干嘛
What?
- 你看上去没那么聪明 - 你也是
- You don't look that smart. - You don't either.
大部分监狱都造在小城镇附近
So most prisons are built around small towns.
不管有多偏远 他们需要物资补给和劳动力
No matter how remote, they need supplies and a work force.
如果我能到达地面
If I can get to the surface,
我就能知道怎样才能翻过围墙离开这里
I'll know what it's going to take to get over the wall, get out of here.
不过你得在禁闭箱里转移他们的注意力
But first I'm gonna need that diversion in the box.
你需要多少时间
How much time do you need?
3到5分钟
Three to five minutes.
这没问题
No problem.
退后
Step back.
我认识你
I know you.
你认识个鬼
You don't know shit, you cunt-eater.
给我退后
Now step back.
现在我想起来了
Now I remember.
什么？
What?
你妈妈 她是我在马拉喀什最喜欢的妓女
Your mother, she was my favorite whore in Marrakesh.
伙计 她的技术真不赖啊
Man, she could polish a helmet!
不
No!
嗨
Hey!
我快要死了 我快要死了
You're killing me! You're killing me!
这是4号箱的画面 长官
Bringing up box four, sir.
他又想干嘛
Now, what is he up to?
嗨 给我闭嘴 你这个德国狗
Hey! Shut the fuck up, you German dog!
总控制室 请指示
Master control, please advise.
稳住他 等我过去
Just hold him till I get there.
2号箱摄像头故障
I've got a camera malfunction, box two.
收到 重启一下系统
Roger that. Just reboot the system.
见鬼
Shit!
给我闭嘴
Shut the fuck up!
我能听见你
- 洛特梅耶 闭嘴 - 要麻醉他吗 长官
- Hey, Rottmayer, shut up! - Restrain and drug him, sir?
等一下
Not yet.
你这头猪
我能听见你
我会把你们杀光
我要把你的眼珠子挖出来
我要阉了你
是的 你等着 是的
把4号箱的灯关了
Lights off, box four.
不 不
我受不了黑暗
把门打开
Now open it.
我害怕
今天不太顺呐
Rough day, Mr. Rottmayer?
上帝宽恕我
我们在天上的父
愿人都尊你的名为圣
愿你的国降临
愿你的旨意行在地上如同行在天上
我们日用的饮食 今日赐给我们
宽恕我们的罪过 如同我们宽恕别人一样
不要让我陷于诱惑
但救我们脱离凶恶
你凶恶 你是魔鬼
你听说过有个疯子
大白天提着灯笼
跑到集市上
他不断地喊 我找上帝
我找上帝
我得回去
Let's get 'em.
你好好听着 我无所谓
Here's what you should know. I don't care.
你早晚会把我想知道的告诉我
Sooner or later you will tell me what I want to know.
这是必然的 就像死亡
It is inevitable. Like dying.
不过记住 将来会有一天 我会对你和你现在做的
But know this, there will come a point where I don't give a shit.
这些破事完全不放在心上
about you or whatever the fuck you think you're doing right now.
祝你愉快 洛特梅耶先生
So have a lovely day, Mr. Rottmayer.
第二层出现紧急情况 第二层出现紧急情况
Emergency personnel to level two. Emergency personnel to level two.
第二层出现紧急情况 长官 电气故障
Valve breach on level two, sir. Electrical malfunction.
长官
Sir?
把货弄出去
Get the assets out of there.
快开门
Open up!
快把门打开 快开门
Open the fucking door! Open the door!
- 成功了吗 - 是的
- Did you make it? - Yeah.
我们在哪儿
Where are we?
- 我们在哪儿 - 我不知道
- Where are we? - I don't know!
见鬼
Fuck.
他们冻结了支票
They froze the check.
你说什么？
What are we talking about here?
给雷的费用 他们冻结了支票
The payment for Ray's services. They froze the check.
没有冻结 延迟兑现了
It's not frozen, it's on hold. All right?
250万的大额交易 出现这种情况很正常
It's very common in a $2.5 million transaction.
不 不 正常情况下只要一周或者十天
No. Common would be a week, maybe 10 days.
这一次时间太长了
This has been way longer than that.
天呐 艾碧 这是联邦政府
Jesus, Abby. It's the federal government.
你知道他们的做法
You know how they work.
联系过那女人吗
Did you call that woman?
是的 联系过了 一切正常
Yeah, I called. Everything is fine.
他在哪儿
Then where is he?
他在做他该做的事情
He is on the job that he was hired to do.
你的意思是一切顺利
So you're saying it's all good?
一切顺利
It's all good.
缺口在哪儿
Where was the breach?
缺口在右舷的压载舱系统里
The auxiliary ballast tank system on the starboard side.
5号和7号隔断被打开了
Compartments five and seven have been compromised.
它们连接到2号箱底下的通风井
And that leads to the ventilation shaft under box two.
普尔图斯
Portos.
铆钉都生锈了
Yeah, they're full of rust.
准是被水压冲上来的
Water pressure must have snapped them clean off.
也许吧
Maybe.
他不叫普尔图斯吧
Portos isn't his name, is it?
怎么没人提醒我？
Why wasn't I alerted?
听着 是这样的 很多人出钱
Look, it's like this. There's a lot of people paying money.
测试监狱是不是牢不可破
to make sure that facility is unbreakable.
他是雷·布雷斯林 逃脱大师雷·布雷斯林
It's Ray Breslin. The great Ray Breslin.
他去那儿 就是为了证明连他也逃不出去
He's there to prove that not even he can get out.
你一定要他永远待在那儿 有问题吗？
You make sure he stays there forever. Do you have a problem with that?
没有 完全不成问题 尽管放心
No. Not at all. Just the opposite.
混蛋
Fucker.
很好 还有一件事
All right, good. There's one more thing.
中国的银行已经加入了巴西 俄罗斯
The Chinese banks have joined the Brazilians, the Russians,
英国 美国 还有瑞士的银行
the English, the U.S. and the Swiss banks.
他们出钱调查曼海姆那家伙的下落
They're all paying to find out the whereabouts of this Manheim fellow.
有传言说他开发了一个程序
Word on the street is that he has developed a program.
要摧毁全世界的银行系统
to turn the entire world banking system into fucking confetti.
洛特梅耶跟那个混蛋一起工作过 他知道曼海姆在哪儿
Rottmayer worked with that asshole. He knows where he is.
你的任务就是撬开他的嘴
Your job is to get that information out of him.
怎么这么巧 自从布雷斯林和洛特梅耶越走越近
Well, itjust so happens that since Breslin has gotten closer to Rottmayer,
洛特梅耶现在的反抗情绪比以前高的多
Rottmayer has developed a new edge to his defiance that wasn't there before.
这都是布雷斯林的错
I think Breslin is to blame.
那就击垮布雷斯林
Then break Breslin.
谢谢
Thank you.
有个任务交给你 你一定会喜欢
I have an assignment I know you'll enjoy.
站起来
Get on your feet!
醒醒 醒醒
Wakey, wakey…
跟我说说话
Talk to me.
坚强点 你必须战斗
Come on. You must fight.
起来
Get up!
给我站好
Stay on your feet!
如果我们在船上 应该有感觉
If we're on a ship, we would know.
不会
No.
这是条1000英尺长200英尺高的船 有稳定性
Not if it was 1, 000 feet long, 200 feet high, with stabilizers.
我们什么也感觉不到
We wouldn't know a damn thing.
醒醒 醒醒 让他站起来
Wakey, wakey! Get him on his feet.
（检索中央情报局数据库 密码无效）
- 你能行的 - 快走
- You can do it. Keep going. - Come on, go. Move it!
- 你要坚持住 - 我们出不去了
We can't get out of here.
- 我们能出去 - 不
- Yes, we can. - No!
给我站起来
Get on your feet!
你必须要坚强
You've got to stay strong.
退后 退后 我让你快走
Back up! Back up! It's you I want. Move it!
人渣
Piece of shit…
住手 德雷克
Stop it now, Drake.
不要投降 别让他们打垮你
Don't give up. Don't let them break you.
你为什么想在监狱里过日子
What made you want to spend your life in prison?
告诉我 是因为什么
Tell me. What made you do it?
告诉我
Tell me!
我以前是律师 是检察官
I was a lawyer. Prosecutor.
有个被我送进监狱的人发誓要报复我
A man lput away made a promise to me.
在牢里的三年 他天天都在计划
This man thought about that promise every day for three years,
计划怎样逃出监狱
planning his way out of prison,
计划将来怎么报复我
planning on how he was gonna keep his word.
被人夺走性命不算什么
Taking a man's life is nothing.
等于夺走一切
That's everything, isn't it?
一切
Everything.
光把坏人送进监狱是不够的
You see, putting people in prison wasn't good enough.
我必须确保他们
And I had to… lwanted to.
永远待在里面 逃不出来
make sure they stayed in there, didn't get out.
我理解你 我有个女儿
I understand. I have a daughter.
我知道那种感受 你有两条路
Never forget them. You have a choice.
你可以死在这里
You can die in here,
或者跟我一起逃出去 惩罚陷害你的人
or you can get out with me and punish who put you here.
听见了吗
You hear me?
是的
Yeah.
有好消息也有坏消息
Good news and bad news.
我一直在想那次会面提到的私人监狱
I was thinking about that first meeting, privatized incarceration.
不受约束 立足国际 纯粹为了盈利 完全非法
Off the grid, international profile. And I started digging.
有前军队的混蛋和黑市公司的渣滓长官
Run by ex-military assholes and Blackwater rejects. You know, bad dudes.
雷八成就在那里
If Ray is anywhere, it's here.
那里是哪里
Where is "here"?
这就是坏消息
That's the bad news.
我不知道
I don't know.
搞不到这里的布局图
No access to any layout.
警卫没有盲点
No blind times.
我们被困在该死的海中央
We're in the middle of the fucking ocean.
不过我好歹摸清了这儿的规律
But I'll be damned if I didn't find a routine.
他们故意弄混警卫的班次 每次都不一样
They scramble the guard shifts so they're never the same.
可是他们没法改变警卫自己的习惯
But they can't change the routine of the guards themselves.
我们不知道警卫几时上班几时下班
We don't know when they start. We don't know when they end.
不过我知道他们按照习惯会做些什么
But I do know where they're gonna be based on habit.
看到那个下楼的家伙吗？发现他走路内八字吗？
See that guy coming down the stairs? See how he walks all pigeon-toed?
鸭子
The Duck.
对 鸭子一直跟那个爱挠脖子的家伙搭档
Yeah. The Duck always works with the guy scratching the back of his neck.
皮炎男
Hives.
对 皮炎男
Yeah, Hives.
这两个人搭档的时候总是绕圈巡逻
When Duck and Hives work together, they always do a circle.
他们会不定时地巡逻
They may do it at random times of day. It doesn't matter when they do it,
但总是在第128步的时候走完一圈 然后这俩人分开 看着
it always ends up being 128 strides, then they split up. Watch.
现在 他们各走一边
Now they each take a side.
鸭子走63步 皮炎男走65步 到顶上会合
Duck walks 63 strides, Hives 65. Then they meet up at the top.
底下那个五大三粗的家伙 他动得不多
The guard down there at the bottom, the heavy-set guy, he doesn't move much.
我猜他在这儿时间比较长 懒得到处走
My guess is he's been here a while and only does what he has to do.
路易莎
Louisa.
Louisa?
他的肥屁股让我想起我第一个女朋友
His fat ass reminds me of my first girlfriend.
不错
Nice.
那边那个警卫是个麻烦
That guard over there could be a problem for us.
他一直东看西看
He's always looking around.
- 小鸡男 - 小鸡男 对
- The Chicken Man. - Chicken Man, right.
我猜小鸡男是新来的 干活一丝不苟
My guess, Chickie's new here. Does everything by the book.
- 怎么知道他们什么时候换班？- 我不知道
- How do you know when the shift ends? - I don't.
我猜这是午饭时间
My guess, it's lunchtime.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
谢谢
Thanks.
我们已经摸清了规律
Now that we've got the routine,
接下来缺个好心的医生 我们在哪儿
we just gotta ask the good doctor where the hell we are.
我没权利给你任何止痛药
I'm not permitted to give you anything for the pain,
所以别问我要
so don't request it.
你是医生 你宣过誓
You're a doctor. You took an oath.
我愿尽我的能力与判断力所及
"According to my ability and judgment,
保护病人免于伤病 不公
"I'll protect my patients from harm and injustice."
（止血粉）
你这样不对
What you're doing here is wrong.
你到底想从我这儿得到什么
What exactly is it you want from me?
我想知道我在哪儿
I want to know where the hell I am.
警卫
Guards!
没事 不要紧
It's okay. It's under control.
把他放回来
Put him back here.
对不起
Sorry.
- 怎么样 - 不成
- So… - No.
再给他点压力
Got to push him harder.
逼得太紧会有反效果
Push him, we'll lose him.
没别的办法了吗
No other options?
我有B计划
Plan B.
总得有个备用计划
You always gotta have a Plan B.
弄到了吗
Did you get it?
现在 我需要他的眼镜
Now I need his glasses.
长官 你来看看这个
Sir? You want to take a look at this?
- 这是什么 - 六分仪
- What's this? - It's a sextant.
当然了
Of course it is.
它管用 用它测出海平面和北极星的夹角
It works. You spot the North Star with the horizon.
不过只能得出纬度
But it will only give us half of our location.
把布雷斯林带来
Bring Breslin.
我会解释怎么用 但得先把它带到甲板上去
I'll explain how it works later, but first we've got to get it topside.
小心
Watch out.
欢迎入住你的新家 布雷斯林先生
Welcome to your new home, Mr. Breslin.
这里是E区
Section E.
就你一个人
Waiting for inmates.
你知道我是谁
You know who I am?
现在知道了
I do now.
我仔细研究过你的著作 写得真好
I've studied your work very closely. It's quite brilliant.
事实上我就是参考了你的著作
As a matter of fact, it's what I used as a reference guide in.
才设计出这座监狱
designing this facility.
既然你知道 快放我走
If you know who I am, let me go.
不不不 布雷斯林先生
No, no, no, no, Mr. Breslin.
事可不是这么办的 这次不是
That's not how this works. Not this time.
花钱把你弄进来的人 希望你永远待在这儿
You see, the people who paid for you to be here want you here forever.
知道了这点 知道了你是谁
And knowing that, and knowing who you are,
不 你曾经是谁
well, who you were…
我就不能再让你和洛特梅耶
I can't have you communicating with Rottmayer,
或者任何其他人说话了
or anybody else, for that matter.
这就是现实 你逃不出去
This is the reality. And there's no way out.
你有两条路
This can go two ways.
放我走 我就当没这回事
You let me go and I'll pretend this never happened.
如果不放 等我出去 我会把这该死的地方烧光
You don't, and I'll burn this fucking place to the ground on my way out.
从现在开始 不许去餐厅 不许放风
Effective right now, no mess, no rec time,
还有不许洗澡
and no showers.
我能帮你找到曼海姆
I can get you Victor Manheim.
洛特梅耶信任我
Rottmayer trusts me.
话虽如此
So you say.
可这还不够
Not good enough.
你有什么损失？找到曼海姆
What have you got to lose? Finding him has got to be worth.
你能拿到的钱比我值的钱要多得多吧
a lot more than what you were paid for me, right, Hobbes?
这个主意不错 不过
It's a nice idea, but.
按照现在的情况 这两份钱我都要
as it stands right now, I'm in line to get both.
你永远打不垮洛特梅耶 他死也不会说的
You'll never break Rottmayer. He'll die before he turns.
你只有靠我才能得到你想要的
I'm your only chance to get what you want.
我要曼海姆和整个组织的信息 名字 目前的位置
I want Manheim and his whole network. Names. Locations in real time.
如果情报属实我就放你走 不过记住
Get that. If it checks out, I'll let you go. But know this.
你必须把洛特梅耶跟你说的每一个字都告诉我
You tell me every word that you and Rottmayer share,
否则我就亲手宰了你
or I will personally pull the fucking life out of you.
很公平
Fair enough.
怎么回事
So what happened?
我打的你这张牌
I'm playing you.
昨天晚上洛特梅耶告诉我
Last night Rottmayer told me he started his network.
曼海姆和他的五个同乡创办了这个组织
with five guys from his hometown.
他说他可以把命交给他们
He said he could trust his life to these guys.
把六分仪给贾韦德
Give Javed the sextant.
告诉他怎么用 说我们能帮他出去
Show him how to use it. Tell him it's his ticket outta here.
贾韦德 他宁可看我们死
Javed. He'd rather see us dead.
他们绝不会怀疑贾韦德
He'll be the last one they suspect.
曼海姆吹嘘过他的组织
He bragged how his network.
六年前如何让冰岛的银行倒闭
caused the bank collapse in Iceland six years ago.
六年前的事情管我屁事 我要知道他现在在哪儿
I don't give a shit about six years ago. I want to know where he is now.
你想死吗
You want to die?
你想出去吗
You want to get out?
今天
Today.
有人在密谋越狱
They're plotting an escape.
越狱？
An escape?
真的吗 谁 什么时候
Really? Who and when?
全部的细节我不清楚
I don't know all the details.
只知道一些
Just some.
把你知道的告诉我
Well, tell me the details you know.
你得先给我点好处
You give me things first.
阿尔弗雷德 阿尔弗雷德先生 管你叫什么名字
Mr. Alfredo, Afridi, or whatever the fuck your name is…
你那些贩毒集团的朋友们花了很多钱 把你送到这儿
Your opium drug cartel friends have paid a lot of money for you to be here.
那是当然的 那些混蛋
Of course they did, those fucks.
你除了想要自由
So aside from your freedom,
你还想要什么
what else can I give you?
我要那些警卫别去管我的人
I want the guards to leave my people alone.
我的牢房里
The Holy Koran…
要有一本可兰经
I want one in my cell.
我要在室外说真主
And I want to say the name of Allah.
和先知穆罕默德的名字
and the prophet Mohammed in the open air.
我要做晚祷的时候
I want to be seen by my God.
真主能够看见我
when I say my evening prayers.
就这些
That's all?
That's all.
我要真主能看见我 霍布斯先生
I want to be seen by my God, Mr. Hobbes!
真主 宽恕我
纬度是30度22分
30 degrees, 22 minutes.
我们在回归线无风带
We're in Horse Latitudes, calm water.
北还是南
North or south?
赤道上方的水流是逆时针方向 所以是北面
Water goes counter-clockwise above the equator, so we're north.
我们怎么弄到经度
How do we get the longitude?
昨天进来一个新犯人 他说昨天是11月20号
They brought a new fish in yesterday. He said it was November 20th.
11月的海上有温暖的雨水和空气
We've got warm rain, warm air at sea in November.
想象你要造一个秘密监狱
Now, you're building a secret facility.
你把它放在海上
You're putting it on the water.
你选择北纬30度 因为你想避开大风大浪
You're at 30 degrees north latitude because you want to avoid rough water.
你不会选加勒比海和太平洋
So you're going to want to stay away from the Caribbean and the Pacific,
或者中国海的东边
say, east of the China Sea.
（摩洛哥）
我敢打赌 我们很可能在摩洛哥的沿海
If I was a betting man, I'd say we could be off the coast of Morocco.
- 你只是猜测 - 国际水域 风平浪静
- It's just a guess. - International waters. Calm sea.
离陆地很近 方便补给 这是有根据的推测
Close enough to land for supplies. Educated guess.
我在卡萨布兰卡认识个人 他欠我个大人情
I know a guy in Casablanca. He owes me big-time.
大到能来救你？
Enough to come and get you?
救我还不够呢
He'd still owe me.
就一个办法能把消息发出去 就一个
There's only one way to get a message out. One way.
我的天呐
My God…
这是什么 你吞了止血粉
What is this? You swallowed clotting powder?
霍布斯的办公室里有本书
In Hobbes' office is a book.
雷·布雷斯林写的 破解监狱安防系统
Compromising Correctional Institution Security by Ray Breslin.
第88页上 有路易斯堡联邦监狱C区牢房的详细介绍
On page 88 is a detailed description of Cell Block C at Lewisburg Federal Prison.
警卫
Guards!
你去看看 想想你的誓言
Check it out. And remember your oath.
我拖不住霍布斯了 得告诉他个位置
I can't stall Hobbes anymore. I've got to give him a location.
可我们还没计划好
But we still don't have a plan.
这就看医生的了
It's in the doctor's hands.
（希波克拉底誓言）
（医学伦理）
医务人员请去三楼审讯室
Medical personnel, Interrogation Three.
警卫
Guards!
把E区的犯人普尔图斯带过来
Bring me prisoner Portos from E Block.
是霍布斯的命令 快去
Hobbes' orders. Do it now.
吸气
Breathe in.
再吸一次
Again.
我看了那本书 你怎么知道的
I saw the book. How did you know?
那本书就是我写的
I'm Ray Breslin. lwrote the book.
医生是这样一群人 对他们开的药所知不多
Doctors are men who prescribe medicines of which they know little.
对这药治疗的疾病所知更少
to cure diseases of which they know less.
而对 用药的人更是一无所知
for men of whom they know nothing at all.
你想要我做什么
What do you want me to do?
医生搞定了 贾韦德该行动了
The doctor is in. Now Javed has to do his part.
曼海姆的主要行动基地在鲁塞城外20英里的地方
Manheim's main base of operations is 20 miles outside of Ruse.
在保加利亚和罗马尼亚的边界上
That's on the Bulgarian-Romanian border.
瞧
See?
出卖朋友没你想得那么难
Ratting out your friends ain't so hard.
在霍布斯意识到那个位置是瞎扯之前 我们有24个小时
We've got 24 hours before Hobbes realizes the Bulgarian location is bullshit.
认识C区的人吗
Who do you know in C Block?
我已经允许你半夜做祷告了
They've given permission for your midnight prayer,
你要回报我什么
so what do you have for me?
- 镜头对准布雷斯林 - 是
- Lock in on Breslin. - Yes, sir.
他在干什么呢
What are we up to?
开响
Louder.
响一点 再响点
Louder. Louder!
拜托你
Got you.
马上破译
Decode it.
（C区转移时发动暴乱）
（24小时内赶到）
（北纬30度22分 西经23度6分）
（明天下午5点整 烧烤泳池派对）
（记住告诉孩子们）
（带上所有玩具）
（洛特梅耶）
停下来
Stop.
放大
Zoom in.
是玛卡玛·哈桑
It's Makmar Hassan.
布雷斯林想让哈桑从C区开始越狱
Breslin is gonna have Hassan start the break from Cell Block C.
我们知道了时间
We have a time frame.
我们知道了位置
And we have a location.
C区牢房
Cell Block C.
增加三倍警卫 查出所有参与的人
Triple the guard force there. I want to know everyone who's involved.
好的 长官
You will, sir.
C区牢房 准备接受检查
Cell Block C, prepare for inspection.
只剩路易莎和小鸡男 其他人都被派到C区牢房了
Louisa and Chicken Man. They sent everyone else to Cell Block C.
但愿你是对的
You better be fuckin' right.
放心吧
Don't worry.
嗨 你这个该死的白种穷鬼婊子
Hey! You fucking white trash scumbag bitch!
要去哪儿 你这个该死的基地恐怖分子同性恋
Where are you going, you fucking towel-head al-Qaeda faggot?
- 你这个该死的秃头 - 去死吧
- Hey, your fuckin' sister gives… - Fuck you, you diaper-head…
- 你这个该死的尿布头 - 狗娘养的
- You fuckin' skinhead! - You motherfuckin'…
C区并没有人越狱
The break was never happening in Block C.
所有人都去巴比伦 快去
All men from C to Babylon. Right now.
快走
Come on!
快上来
布雷斯林到哪儿去了
Where the fuck is Breslin?
快快快 快走
Go, go, go! Let's move!
11分钟内赶到甲板上 但愿医生联系上人了
We've got 11 minutes to get topside. Let's hope the doc made contact.
快走 快
Go. Go.
你干什么
What are you doing?
摄像头都连在一起 得把它们关掉
All the cameras are connected. We've gotta block 'em out.
长官
Sir!
笑一个
Say "cheese."
走吧
Come on.
行了 就是这儿 我们走
Okay. All right, this is it. Let's go.
启动5号安全协议
Engage security protocol five.
启动封锁程序
是全面封锁 都被锁在里面了
It's a full lockdown. We're all locked inside.
还有8分钟
Eight minutes.
他们没招了
They're out of moves.
德雷克 带两队人 把耗子全部抓回笼子里
Drake, take two units. Drag the rats back to their cages.
等等
Hold up.
贾韦德
Javed!
打开3号门 抓住他们
Open gate three! Take 'em!
快 快快快 别让他们跑了
Go, go, go, go! Don't fucking lose them!
布雷斯林
Breslin!
把门打开 你这个混蛋
Breslinl Open before I break you, you motherfucker!
你别想活着出去 你这个狗娘养的
You'll never get out of here alive, you arsehole!
- 我会宰了你 - 我们得快走
- We're gonna kill you! - We've gotta move!
把门弄开 我从另一边进去
Smash that door down. I'll come around from the other side.
他们怎么会知道我们在这儿
Breslin, how the hell do they know where we are?
你不是把摄像头都关了吗
You turned off the cameras, right?
运动探测器
Motion detector.
长官
Sir!
让开
Out.
你可以玩上一整天 布雷斯林 可一切都在我的控制中
You can play your games all day, Mr. Breslin, but I'm still in control.
不管你做什么都没用
Whatever you do, I have the power.
你逃不出我的掌心
I own your ass.
你们得爬到梯子上去
You guys have gotta get up that ladder.
我去找轮机舱 把电控关掉
I've got to find the engine room and shut the power grid down.
在备用发电机开始工作之前
Those magnetic locks will stay open for about.
有5秒钟的时间 磁力锁是打开的
five seconds before the back-up generator kicks in.
你们只有这点时间出去
You understand? That's all the time you're gonna have.
拿着这个 拿着
Take this. Take it.
你是个好人
You're a good man.
快去吧
Go do it.
- 你怎么办 - 我会出去的
- What about you? - I'll be right behind you.
万一你5点还没上甲板呢
What if you're not on the deck at 5:00?
你该干嘛干嘛 我还有B计划
Do what you've got to do. There's always Plan B.
跟我走 我们一起出去
Come on. Let's do it.
不用了 我出不去的
We're dead men. There's no way out.
- 跟我一起走 - 我爬不上梯子
- Come with me. - I won't make it up that ladder.
- 我背你上去 - 我要去拖住他
- I'll carry you up the ladder. - But I can hold them back.
- 我不会丢下你的 - 把枪给我
- I'm not gonna leave you behind. - Give me your gun.
快把枪给我
Just give me your gun.
真主保佑你
Allah be with you.
我们上面见
I'll see you up there.
快走吧
Now go.
小心点
Take care.
我们究竟在找什么 长官
该死
Fuck!
报告情况
Report?
你这混蛋
Fuck you, you motherfucker!
我们在下甲板受到攻击
We're taking gunfire on the lower deck!
如果他逃到下甲板 一定是去轮机舱
If he made it to the lower deck, he's going to the engine room.
跟我在轮机舱会合 我马上下去
Meet me in the engine room. I'm coming down.
明白
Copy.
- 把那个混蛋弄出来 - 是 长官
- Get that fucker out of there! - Yes, sir.
安全
Clear!
真主至大
是啊 随你怎么说
Yeah. Whatever.
透不过气来了吗？
Having trouble breathing?
我要杀了你 混蛋
I'm gonna fucking kill ya, motherfucker!
滚开
Back off!
- 看见他吗 - 是的 他在这儿
- Did you see him? - Yeah, he's here.
不 等一下
No, wait, wait!
（确认关闭电源）
（关闭）
它还在左舷 长官
He's still on port, sir.
这是怎么回事？
What the fuck?
快走 趴下
Go! Get down!
我们这里有情况
We have a situation up here!
见鬼
Fuck!
快 快
Go, go!
（水燃料转换系统）
谁都别想离开这艘船
No one gets off this ship.
格杀勿论
Shoot to kill.
快 快
Go, go!
- 我们得赶快走 - 现在还不行
- We have to go now! - Not yet!
投降吧 布雷斯林先生
Give yourself up, Mr. Breslin.
你可以到处跑 弄出点动静
You can run around, make some noise…
洒点血
Spill some blood.
可你出不去
You can't get out.
真的
Not really…
我知道你太太和你儿子
I know about your wife, your son.
我一清二楚
I know every detail.
谢谢你指出了我作品中的小小不足
So thank you for pointing out all the small flaws in my creation.
我会修正加强
I'll be sure to fortify them.
但你的时间到了
But your time's up.
听见吗
You hear me?
布雷斯林
Breslin?
你的时间到了
Yourtime is up.
里面 外面 彻底搜查这个房间
No one in. No one out. Search every inch of this fucking room.
重新启动电源
And power this thing back up!
快上 快上
Come on! Let's go, let's go!
- 快起飞 - 快走
- Let's roll! - Go!
（重启系统 冲洗水箱）
布雷斯林
Breslin!
下降
Go down!
快点 快走 下去 下去
Come on, let's go! Down, down!
危险 我们得赶紧走
We're gonna have to back off!
洛特梅耶 枪
Rottmayer! Gun!
- 枪 - 把你的枪给我
- Gun! - Give me your gun!
（易燃品）
嘭
Boom.
祝你愉快 混蛋
Have a lovely day, asshole!
（摩洛哥海岸 距西迪伊夫尼以南10公里）
现在干嘛？
Now what?
轻松一点
Relax.
你以前见过她
You met her before.
杰西卡·梅耶 很荣幸见到你
Jessica Mayer. It's an honor to meet you.
你代表了这个领域的最高水平
Your work is the gold standard in the field.
她是我在中情局里的耳目
She has been my eyes and ears inside the Agency.
你好 爸爸
Hello, Dad.
她也是我的女儿
And she's also my daughter.
你好 亲爱的
Hello, darling.
谢天谢地 你逃出来了
Thank God you made it.
我好想你
I missed you.
你怎么了
What happened?
喔 没什么 不用担心
Nothing. Don't worry about it.
你就是曼海姆
You're Manheim.
我居然没想到
Didn't see that coming.
你该想到
You should've.
是啊
Yeah.
怎么做到的
How'd you do it?
我们有代号
We have code names.
代号洛特梅耶 表示被关在高度戒备的监狱里
Code name Rottmayer meant maximum security incarceration.
我爸爸被抓的时候激活了这个代号
When my dad was picked up, it activated the code.
你在这时候联系了克拉克
And that's when you called Les Clark.
我要找最好的人 你同意接受这份工作后
I needed the best. And after you agreed to do it,
那个名字其实是身份代号
And the name you gave me was the I.D. code.
普尔图斯
Portos.
洛特梅耶 埃米尔·洛特梅耶
Rottmayer. Emil Rottmayer.
然后我成为你最好的朋友
And I became your best friend.
跟你合作实在太难了 我可费老劲了
You are not user-friendly. I had to work very hard.
还有那该死的禁闭箱 真是热死我了
And that damn box. That was hot.
我觉得还好啊
It did get warm, yeah.
无所谓了 重要的是我们现在都出来了
But it doesn't matter. What matters is that I'm out and so are you.
里面的日子真够受的
We both served enough time.
咱们重新来过
You want to try it again?
你这混蛋
You son-of-a-bitch…
希望不用再见到你了
I hope I never see you again.
好伤心呐
That hurts.
还有件事
One more thing!
克拉克到底知道多少
How much did Les really know?
起先只知道我告诉他的
Only what I told him, at first. But the next thing I know,
不过 后来我发现他绕开我
he's gone around me.
向活人墓的投资人提供服务
and offered his services to the backers of The Tomb.
所以他知道我被送到哪儿
So he knew where I was being sent?
是他安排的运输
He arranged your transport.
要搭车吗
Need a ride?
不了 谢谢 我自己有安排
No, thanks. I made my own arrangements.
事情蹊跷 我们感觉很不对劲
Wasn't tracking. We knew something wasn't right.
（营利性非法监狱大曝光）
那个地方危机四伏
Red flags going up all over the place.
克拉克却显得过分淡定 我们就开始调查
Clark was too calm about it, so we started digging.
原来有人想请他做
We found out he'd been offered the CEO job.
活人墓项目的首席执行官
of running the whole Tomb program.
如果那个样板监狱被证明牢不可破
if the prototype you were buried in proved inescapable.
他就能拿到500万年薪和优先认股权
At a salary of $5 million a year, plus stock options.
追踪到他了吗
Tell me you tracked him down.
照你的吩咐 这会儿行动已经开始了
Just like you asked. The plan's in motion as we speak.
（佛罗里达州 迈阿密）
该睡觉了 混蛋
It's sleepy-time, motherfucker.
他妈的
Oh, fuck!
不不不 快发动 发动 发动啊
No, no… Come on, come on, come on…
见鬼
Fuck!
雷
Ray!
该死的
Fuck!
雷
Ray!
- 是哈什 - 他说什么
- It's Hush. - What did he say?
一切顺利
It's all good.
很好
Good.
- 那是什么 - 新工作
- What's that? - Job offers.
晚点再看吧 我们一起吃顿特别的晚餐吧
Maybe later. Why don't you and me have a very special dinner.
我来做饭
I'll cook.
嫌我遭的罪还不够吗？
Haven't I suffered enough?